All right. What is up, my friends?
Welcome to the complete set review for
Reality Fractured. Also, give Brian a
hand. That's the coolest intro ever.
Right. That was really, really cool. And
we're going over every card in the
entire set. And I am absolutely pumped
for this set. Uh, of course, an in
universe set is very exciting, but the
story here is really, really cool. The
mechanics are really cool, too, as far
as how they line in. We'll see more of
that obviously as we go into it. So over
every card in the entire set for
constructed and for limited giving out
the awards you know and love, bested
show, trap card, sleeper card, and bomb
in common. Uh and uh it's going to be
great. Really good stuff. Broken up into
seven sections on YouTube and of course
all here live on Twitch. So make sure if
you're here for the first time uh
follow, like, comment, subscribe,
buttons, do the things. Uh a lot of work
goes into set review and your support
makes that possible. So please uh don't
be shy about that. So, real fast remind
you we got 10 new brews coming up next
Wednesday on early access where you'll
see me playing these cards and
constructive for the first time. That's
a blast. And then, of course, on the
release day, we'll be doing our first
drafts for bronze to mythic. That'll be
Tuesday uh 29th at 8:00 p.m. So, both
those uh going to be a lot of fun.
Really, really cool. And we're brought
to you by Rogue Energy. I got my Rogue
right here. Uh I'm big a big hydration
guy and uh of course you like caffeine,
check out the energy line. Hydration
line, however, is uh great for me. Uh,
no sugar, no caffeine, five calories.
Great stuff. Super sale right now for
today, Friday, tomorrow, Saturday, and
the day after Sunday, for this weekend
only. 30% off. Use the code, not 20%,
but actual 30% off, which is a great
deal. Check them out. Uh, really awesome
stuff. You get a tub. It's like 20 25
bucks. 20 bucks with the promo code last
you forever. Great. Awesome stuff. Rogue
energy. Good stuff. So, uh, let's hop in
and get into white. Before we start
though, we have uh one important thing
to go over and that is this Jace
Planaineswalker token. That's right. So,
this is uh one of the really cool parts
of the set is that we're going to see
this Jace token literally everywhere. Uh
there's a bunch of cards in the set that
have the empower Jace mechanic, meaning
that they it's kind of like a mass army
uh in the Hobbit or Lord of the Rings or
War of the Spark where if you don't have
a Jace, you make one and then whatever
the empower mechan uh mechanic number
is, you add that many loyalty counters
and it's a planaineswalker token. It's
pretty simple actually where it's just
minus one to surveil one or minus three
to draw a card. That's it. So, it's not
like Planaineswalkers everywhere kind of
like in War of a Spark where like
there's just bio planes walkers on play
all the time. It's really really
confusing because this is almost sort of
like a glorified clue. Uh, which is kind
of awesome honestly. And the empower
Jace X mechanic kind of just tacks on
either draw a card, surveil, or gain
some amount of life onto these spells
because your opponent wants to attack it
or not. But it's super interactive where
your opponent can just choose to attack
it or choose to leave it alone. You can
choose to save it up or use it for other
things. So, really, really fun. Uh,
you're going to see a Jason play a lot
of a time on both sides of the board in
limited, which is really fun. Uh, I've,
spoiler alert, I've played with the set
before. I recorded some, uh, some early
access content, which you'll be seeing
soon enough, which is great. Uh, but
it's really, really cool. Uh, very, very
fun, unique mechanic with lots of
choices on both sides as far as how you
want to use it, how you want to attack
it. So, anytime you see empower Jace,
you'll see this token. I want to go over
that first um, before we get started
into our white section. So going into
white, we see our first empower empower
chase card, right? So uh look at that.
Good planning on my part, right? Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Academic ascent is two mana
for an instant plus two plus two engage
flying of turn empower Jace 2. So again
two counters on this Jace token and as a
reminder that is 2/3 of a card, right?
Because minus three is draw card. So if
you combine this with some other
empowered dis effect, you can get a
draw. Otherwise you can get two
surveill. So imagine this is just like a
trick with sort of like a clue built in
sort of or multiple surveillance buil
built in depending on how you want to
use it which is really cool. Uh it's
really fun to evaluate uh based on
gameplay and then deck building how
you're going to be able to use this. And
this is a you know a fine card also not
particularly amazing. Just your typical
like limited you know combat trick. It's
not that exciting. Giving flying is
cool. Um you know just a jump for the
win you know in an aggro deck is kind of
sweet. Uh and then if you're playing
more Jay stuff it will draw cards too.
So fine limited trick and a good
introduction to the empower Jace
mechanic.
Next up we have blossom blessed angel
showing off some more of the mechanics
of a set format for a two four common
flying vigilance creature and the
prepared mechanic returns from stricks
haven. So this is the mechanic where
there's a spell on the creature. This is
kind of the opposite of adventure uh
where with adventure you play the spell
first get the creature later. Uh, with
prepared, you play the creature and if a
creature is in play and prepared, then
you can cast the spell and unprepare it.
So, this comes already prepared. Uh,
some need to meet a condition, some are
already prepared. This one's already
there. And it comes with seed suture one
green white hybrid sorcery. Put a
counter on a creature and you gain one
life. And definitely a uh a big time
indictment of power love power creep on
creatures unlimited uh where this is a
baseline two four flying vigilance for
four that can be a three five and gain a
life and do synergy stuff the next turn
and it's probably still only just an
okay card. Uh you know seems fine
probably a card you're not super excited
for. There are so many uncommons rares
and mythics in uh play packs um these
days that you can usually do better in
your four drop slot. Okay. Uh, so
probably a fine card. Not going to be,
if you're an old school limited player,
you see this, you go, Jesus, this is
insane. But not going to be as great
overall. Cool thing here though is
you're going to see this prepared spell
seed suture more than once. It's
actually on multiple cards, which is a
cute way to kind of keep the complexity
down, uh, which is nice. So fine,
limited common, not a high pick, mostly
a filler, but I think this card's not
embarrassing at all. Pretty solid card.
Campus Crier, however, is our first
award of the season. Bombing common
campus crier is awesome. Two meta 4 a
3-1. It's a human adviser. Has the
ability one mana exiles card from your
graveyard. Empower Jace 2. So
effectively this is pay one and surveil
at least one if not two. And then if you
put it together with any other Jace
effect, it'll be drawing a card. Three
one for two that draws a card from the
graveyard is kind of insane honestly. Uh
really really solid little two drop. Uh
can build card advantage. And again,
don't forget how empowered Jace works
where say you play this and you don't
have another empower Jace and you just
surveil one and leave a Jace on one in
play. Now, if your opponent attacks it
for two or three, you've also gained two
or three life. Uh it's a choice they
have to make, of course. Uh but that's a
great place to be. So, I think Campus
Crier is awesome. A fantastic two drop.
Really, really good. If you happen to
have some sort of like discard or
graveyard synergy, all the better. But
even on base rate, this card is awesome.
Bomb in common for white is campus crier
probably not playable constructed but
honestly it's so cheap if it was some
like super looting heavy deck I don't
think it's insane this card this card
not constructed
then we have fate shaper aspirant five
mana 4 a 34 when it enters choose one
return a legendary card from your
graveyard to your hand or put a plus
encounter on target creature and it
gains vigilance and indestructible until
end of turn not bad for a common uh a
three four gravedigger for is not too
shabby. There are obviously a ton of
legends in the uh in the set. So, it can
return a lot of those. It's al legendary
card, not just legendary creature. Uh
so, there are plains walkers and other
legendary permanency you can return,
which is pretty cool. And then, um
there's some counter synergy, too. So,
the the plus one plus one ability is not
as exciting, but can be more important
as far as pushing damage through or
forcing blocks. And uh this is obviously
kind of a filler level card where like
you're not taking as high in your drafts
ever, but it's a respectable card. think
this card's totally reasonable. There
are also legendary enchantments, even
some rare legendary artifacts. So, a lot
of ways to use this card, which is
sweet. Uh, so solid little common, not
super exciting. Uh, but very, very
reasonable.
Next up, we have graft surgeon. Doctor,
can I get a doctor? The metaphor, a tutu
human cleric enters the plus counter on
it, and when it dies, you get to
modular. Any modular fans out there?
>> Pointless nostalgia.
>> No. Any old school players? uh you get
to modular the counter onto a different
creature. So the red white uh set theme
is uh kind of puzzle musc counter stuff
like that. So kind of a red white card
definitely a filler level common. It's
not that exciting. I think if you're
really doing the thing this card is fine
that means you should never take this
card basically you know higher than
almost last pick. You'll just get it for
free if you are that deck. So um you
know low power level common kind of
draft filler uh is what it is.
Hex Haven Battalion, however, is a great
one. Uh, Land Cyclers returned and once
again, they are actually good. Uh, kind
of like in Marvel. Uh, because they
haven't been good for like the last five
years. They've been mostly awful. Uh,
but now we have basic land cycling back.
So, no color in the cost. Can get any
basic, which is huge. Uh, and the spell
is quite good, too. Hex Haven Battalion
is six mana for a sorcery. Make three
two cadet tokens and then also empower
Jace 2. So, surveil one, maybe draw a
card if you have you have some other
empower Jace. A lot of empower Jace two
in the set, which is a really fun number
because it means you need to kind of
like combo these up and like your
opponent will have a chance to interact
or not. Should they attack the Jace? I
think it's going to play really really
well. And this card is great. Uh, this
is just, you know, six mana for three
twos and a scry is fantastic. Uh,
Imperial Oath was the card in in Neon
Dynasty, I believe. That was awesome.
Card is going to play a lot better than
it looks. It's also a mana fixture,
which is great. Uh, this card's
excellent. Really, really good card. Um,
there's a lot of gold cards in this set
and a lot of dual lands, too. Meaning,
this might end up being more of like a
two-color set. The Hobbit was extremely
two-color. Uh, just like you were one of
the five pairs or some offcolor pair and
that was it. Very little splashing. Uh,
now we're getting back in a kind of
splashy world, I think, with these land
cyclers and these dual lands and all
five color pairs. So, card's great. Um,
one of the best land cyclers, Hex Haven
Battalion,
and it's Memory Trap, which is just the
19th version of uh of uh Banishing
Light.
>> This is getting out of hand.
>> And uh yeah, I mean, Banishing Light's
really really good. This is probably the
top white common. Uh even though I think
that the uh the Campus Crier is the
bombing common and we'll we'll see, but
you know, O-ring's great. Uh very very
good. You know what it does. Predictive
preparations, man. Travel prep is uh
getting a little glowed down here. Two
mana for a sorcery. Put two counters on
each of one of one or two dark creatures
and then flashes back for four. So,
travel prep was an old card from uh
Innistrad. That was this is this exact
card for a green and one flashing back
for a white and one. So, four mana
flashback is a lot more than two. Go was
kind of insane. Uh whereas this card is
a little less insane. Like we said,
there is some plusment synergy in the
Boris uh archetype. That being said, I
think this card is mostly just okay. Um,
I think it's fine. I think it'll play
all right, but it's kind of clunky.
Looking for a way to push things
through? Sure. If you have some other
way to kind of bin stuff, whatever,
that's kind of fine as well. But
overall, I think this card is just kind
of medium. Modern day limited creatures
also don't really need need the help
that much like because they're all so
big anyway. So, I think this card is
just okay. Hey, it's going to play worse
than you think it will in limited. Um,
that's really it.
Shatter Wing Pegasus three mana 4 a two
three flyer five mana pump the team.
This is just like your classic limited
common of it's just a kind of a filler
common you know three mana wind drake
change the numbers around a little bit
and that five mana pump effect. This is
just a uh you know your usual uh your
usual mana sync when you're when you're
flooding out cards fine. Uh just kind of
limited filler though. Two three is
better a lot better than two two but
still kind of whatever.
Surgical precision however is awesome
man for a sorcery choose one strike
creature with four or greater gain one
life or just draw a card and gain two
life. So this sort of reprisal like kill
a big creature effect is often a little
finicky and limited uh because you you
hate have the risk of I don't have any
target so this doesn't do anything.
That's a problem. The this is twofold
though where one as creatures get bigger
and bigger and bigger it's just so much
easier to find its target and this is a
great buyout too just man to draw a card
and gain two life when the green white
archetype is all about kind of life gain
triggers is really really good so this
card's excellent uh one of the best
white commons card's fantastic I would
not be surprised if this is one of the
highest win rate cards in the set on
untapped and 17 lens uh because folks
are going to undervalue it uh but card's
great unflinching hornmancer our first
ever common a Johnny's pride mate I
think don't quote me on it to metaphor a
2-1 uh human cleric with ward one
whenever you gain life put a counter
creature so a Johnny's pride mate and uh
that's cool again this is going to be a
great card limited for the green white
decks kind of a fine card overall you
know a little life gain here and there
for constructive there's a lot of life
gain stuff already happening in standard
uh and there's a bunch more in this set
too so would not be surprised if the
life gain uh deck gets a pretty big ups
grade in standard where it's already
like a tier 2 deck. Uh and ward one is
nice here, you know, kind of getting
that one turn reprieve hopefully of
keeping it alive and then making it big.
And for you popper players out there,
have fun. You now have a pride mate to
play with. Uh pretty cool stuff. Card's
great. Uh great little common and we'll
see a good amount of play across various
formats. Moving on to the uncommons. If
you haven't noticed, we're doing all the
commons and uncommons, rares and
mythics. Me and Nicole decided to
structure it this way. You like it this
way. I think I like this a lot better
personally. Let me know what you think
on it, of course. And our first uncommon
is Denitha, Sword of Hope. Am I saying
it wrong?
>> You're saying it wrong.
>> I don't think I am. I think I'm saying
it right. But, uh, three metaphor a two
first strike whenever you cast an
equipment spell or spell a target, a
creature you control,
draw a card, uh, which is awesome. Only
once a turn, though. So, uh, any pump
spell, any equipment. That's pretty
cool. There'sn't like a ton of that in
the in the format, but there's enough uh
spells to target things. We'll see uh
later. If you draw one card of us,
you're pretty happy. Um and this is our
first of many mirrored pairs. So, what
what is that? So, the conceit of reality
fracture is that Jayce has created this
alternate reality uh kind of planer
chaosesque if you're an older player.
Kind of like Marvel What If you're not
an older player. uh where there are
versions of legends that are uh the
baseline. This is what they look like in
the real world. This is, you know,
Dothena or whatever the hell it's called
is a is a a car we saw in Dominaria.
Very similar type, you know, 22 for
three, some equipment based stuff,
whatever. We're also going to see a
mirrored pair version of this in some in
a different color that has similar
abilities and same name kind of show
what happened in this alternate world of
his character. And we're seeing this
everywhere across the entire set.
There's a bunch of these. The there are
planes walkers. So there's a red a
Johnny and a white a Johnny uh and so on
and so forth. White Liliana, black
Liliana as kind of the major point of
the set. That also changes how packs are
correlated uh in this set. So there's
going to be any booster pack you open
will always have one complete mirrored
pair. So, it'll have if you open up the
the the whatever this card is called, uh
you'll see the other pair of it, and
then a third pair cards, a wild card to
make it not obvious what you took in
limited. So, there's a third kind of
random one. So, there's two of the same
pair and one other one. So, if I open a
Johnny red and Johnny White in limited,
if I took the Johnny Red and passed it,
you know what I what I took, there's a
third one there to muck it up, just so
you know. So, that's how that works. Uh
but yeah, this card is not really good
enough constructed. uh just too small
and frail and unlimited will work if you
have a lot of targeting effects or
equipments which is kind of whatever. So
kind of a cool card a little
underpowered because the stat line's
kind of meh. Uh that's going with the
mirrored pair of things. We'll see we'll
see a bunch of those across the uh the
entire set. Then we have generous
revival. Speaking of Liliana here, this
is uh a look at the white Liliana uh
doing what white Liliana wants to do
which is met up for a sorcery. Turn your
card mana value three graveard to your
battlefield uh with a possible counter
on it and flashback for five. It's kind
of like the helping hand effect. Pretty
clunky for constructive because we
already have literal helping hand as
well as a saga from the Hobbit. So, more
of a limited card, fine. Limited card,
not amazing. I don't love cards like
this in limited, but the flashback gives
some card advantage is kind of cool. Uh,
so yeah, I think a fringe limited card
and not too much more. If you want to
bring bring back an Oculus and standard,
there are better ways to do it.
Then we have Gala the immovable. So, of
course, Galta is the uh the well-known
big green stompy uh dinosaur. Well, this
is the mirrored pair version of Gula.
There's there's a Gala in green as well
at Uncommon. And this is the version
from the the Echoverse, the kind of
weird whatif version. So, while Galta
cares about power, usually Galta the
immovable has got a big ass.
Nine mana for an 07 cost X less to cast
where X is the greatest toughness among
creatures you control rather than power.
And then creatures you control can
attack as though they had didn't have
defender. And each creature you control
with toughness greater than its power
assigns combat for its toughness rather
than its power. So this card is pretty
sweet. Honestly, this is like Doran the
siege tower. Anyone?
Any any Dorian fans out there?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> I'm one personally. Uh but uh and then
it's also uh then you can make all of
your your your walls attack and then
make all your big butts attack cards
kind of sweet honestly. uh if you're
doing some sort of weird like toughness
based thing that's typically not good
enough in constructed but it's hasn't
been that far off you know and uh this
card's sweet and um yeah cool card for
sure definitely a good card limited it's
just huge just it's six of seven seven
with some upside uh but constructed wise
they'll probably be a 10 new brew with
this with this card I would be surprised
although there is a lot of fun stuff
stuff to build around in this set so
we'll see but yeah really fringe
constructed card but great limited card
which is cool and there is actually a
Laura in standard. You're correct. Uh
it's in uh Lurin Eclipse. That's cool.
Then we see Cth the mirrored Cth of
course. Cth the uh the heavily mono red
planaineswalker has uh chosen a
different way of life here as a white
guard. Cth of the homestead through
metaphor a 23 has landfall. Whenever you
uh play a land you gain a life. Whenever
a plains enters put a bus encounter on
target creature. So kind of a mono white
payoff which is not really not really a
thing of course but unlimited cards kind
of nice honestly. play this thing, play
a land, put a counter somewhere, I gain
a life. Scales well as the game goes on.
Not an overtly powerful card, but pretty
solid. Solid card for sure. Fine limited
card.
Then we have Prophesized End.
And I think this card is kind of great.
There are cards I think I'm a little
more excited about in white uh as far as
think cards I think that I think are
sleepers or like you know or have a very
unique effect but I think this card as
far as all around you know just
playability goes this card is fantastic.
Prophesize end is two mana and instant
destroy a creature period that's it no
downside but if it wasn't attacking its
controller draws a card. So, the typical
sort of white removal spell with a
drawback, you know, get lost and erode.
If you know me, you know I'm not usually
a fan of those cards. Uh, but this one
has a mode where you're very happy to
use it in a control deck, right? Where
destroy a target attacking creature for
two mana is pretty good. Not amazing,
but pretty good. The fact that you can
cash in otherwise with this card, uh,
and if you have to use it outside of
combat, you can you can kind of control
it is pretty awesome. And aside from
that, there's also synergy here too
where what if you have a Nars in play or
what if you have a fairy mastermind or
something like that or whatever else it
might be. Uh and then you could of
course kill your own creature and draw a
card too. So there's a little bit of a
little bit of stuff here or there as
well. Uh I think this card's really
sweet. Uh definitely more for defensive
decks, although if you are offensive,
you don't mind the drawback as much if
you're just killing a thing and then
killing them. So I think this card's
sweet. Uh really really solid card. It
is entering the format with a lot of
competition uh from both erode and get
lost when it comes to like the drawback
white removal spell. But this is the
best one for a control deck by a wide
margin. Uh cuz you know 75% of the time
you're going to play with her two killer
thing and move on with your life. So
card's great uh good and limited too. Um
but yeah, constructor wise think this
card is pretty nice. And best in show is
prophesized end. We'll see if I eat my
words here as a noted get lost hater.
But you know if I do you can you can
come make fun of me. Okay.
Then we have refute destiny to meta for
a sorcery and this is a color hoser for
the allied colors. A thing we don't
really see basically ever. To sorcery
exile creature planes walker. It's green
or blue surveil one. So usually color
hoses are enemy colors of course. Uh and
color hoses are great. This of course
being a sorcery makes it a little bit
worse, but exiling that big blue a big
blue planaineswalker, that big green
creature is pretty awesome. Exile is
great, too. And surveil one's nice.
Sorcery speed is a little bit of a
bummer. This is more of a, you know, a
fine tool than a blunt object. You'd
board a bunch of copies of it in, but
card's cool. It, you know, very narrow.
Uh, obviously it will have a place if it
has a place, but is what it is. And for
for limited, good cyborg card. Don't be
shy. Ive best of three limited folks uh
to uh make sure you bring this card in
in your pre-release, you know, be aware.
Rescue Girl first responder. So, who is
who is this? What's going on here? Um
Maser Girl looks a little bit different.
The metaphor, a one- three flyer. Tap to
return another permanent you control to
its owner's hand only during your turn.
And kind of an interesting card where
like a lot of these uncommon legends,
the sizing is not great. uh one three
fly over three is pretty awful. Uh and
then you know it is uh you can't use on
your opponent's turn. Doesn't have haste
but can do some cool like you know
exceed bounce your own stuff and replay
it kind of things. Definitely not good
enough for constructed. Uh but as far as
uh limited goes could be cool if you are
doing some sort of bounce ETB thing. I
think overall they're kind of eh. So not
for constructed and kind of e for
limited is what it is.
Sahili. This is the white f the console
of oversight mana for a 44 flyer. So
okay that one. Whenever you scry or
surveil create a plus a one one thopter
uh token uh but only once a turn.
>> That's a bummer. Uh but scrying and
surveilling is the fateold limited
archetype in this set. So there are many
things that scry and surveil to help
turn this on. Not a constructed card at
all, but it's a fine limited card. You
know, if you're able to kind of play
this and get a a scrier surveil or two,
make some tokens. pretty cool. Uh but
yeah, otherwise just kind of fine like
limited limited filler could do better.
Teao light shield expert met for a one-1
flash when Teao enters target you
control gains hex proof until end of
turn and gets a plus counter on if it's
a creature or a loyalty counter if it's
a planaineswalker. So kind of has uh
empower Jace one if you wanted to. And
uh this card's pretty good. two mana for
this kind of effect is a lot uh where
usually you know you want snakeskin veil
the one mana effect because one mana is
a lot easier to hold up than two mana
and won't start your development either.
Uh so that makes this card a little
rough little worrisome that this card is
just kind of like kind of clunky for a
one one for two but it's a pretty cool
card pretty unique effect um being able
to save your stuff. It's a human, which
might matter for some, you know, kindred
stuff. But yeah, I think this card's
fine. A card that will definitely blow
you out limited. Um, but also like, you
know, maybe you just don't ever really
get a chance to use it properly or
whatever. I think it's pretty good, but
a little underwhelming. Uh, I think it's
fine.
Thalia, the survivor. Bit of a glow down
here again. Another one of the mirrored
pairs. Four mana four, a three four
lifelink with the Thalia ability. Uh a
four manathalia is you know a lot worse
than a two manathalia. Um so not a
playable constructed. It's a fine
limited card. Three four lifelink for
four is a fine limited stat line. And
there is a I'm sorry it's asymmetrical.
I'm stupid.
>> YOU MUST BE SO EMBARRASSED. [screaming]
>> THAT MAKES IT better even. So in
constructed still doesn't matter. Um but
for limit of this card is pretty good.
uh being one-sided three four life for
for four. There are of course either
synergy with in green white with life
gain in red white with buffing things
up. Uh so there are ways to kind of pump
it up and get some value off of it. So
solid card, solid limited card
constructed. I don't think it's good
enough. Then we have tonic orzav law
mage. Yeah, all these white colors cops,
right? It's better for a 2-1 like right
for a 2-1. Uh, flying. Oh,
>> that's just lazy writing.
>> Planes walkers you control have no more
than one creature can attack this
planaineswalker each combat and they can
tap to give a creature with a plus one
plus counter on it flying until end of
turn. I mean, a two on fire for two
upside obviously fine in limited. This
is not a constructed card at all.
Unlimited, it's okay. Again, your your
red white deck that cares about
counters. Uh, a way to jump your things
in the air for those last few points is
kind of cool. That being said, if you're
tapping this to jump your counter
creature and attack rather than just
attacking for uh for um two in the air,
not a big upgrade. And yeah, aren't you
the player of Planaineswalker?
>> Somebody's playing a prank on me,
>> right? Like I I am the Planaineswalker.
I'm I'm That's who I am. That's what I'm
doing here in this game. I am
Planaineswalking into the game.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> So, I don't know. There'll be a little
flavor a little flavor fail here. Uh but
yeah, card's okay. Okay, limited card.
That's really it.
And then we come to these really really
cool enchantments. So this is the uh the
empower Jace mechanic to a whole new
level. Uh I believe there's two of these
in each color. These are the way
enchantments. First is way of the
healer. This is a Liliana enchantment.
They have alternate Liliana. Full mana
for an enchantment. When way of the
healer enters, empower Jace five. So
it's at least going to draw one card and
leave adjacent play with two. It has
planes walkers you control have minus
two make it two two and surveil one. So
this is really cool as there's 10 of
these enchants in the set that can give
your Jace planaineswalker other
abilities which is sick cuz it's very
simple on the baseline but these things
can add a little bit of complexity which
makes it really really interesting as
far as a gameplay piece which I love. Uh
awesome. So, as it stands, if you just
look at this at total face value, it's
for mana, make a 22, make a 22, surveil
one. But of course, it's so much more
than that uh as a card, which is really,
really cool. I think this card looks
awesome and limited for constructed. I
don't think this card is good enough.
Maybe if you're playing a
Planaineswalker deck and you want to
have all your planans walkers the minus
make two twos, sure. So, I don't think
that's good enough. But for a limited
card is really, really cool and quite
good.
The other way in white is the way of the
mentor. So this is the properly colored
Johnny uh effect. Three mana four and
enchantment again empower Jace five
which is great for three mana. Whenever
you gain life, put a loyalty counter on
each planaineswalker you control. That's
like kind of cool honestly as a way to
really bump planaines walkers up and
you're getting enough at face value
which is a big deal. Uh of course you
know Delinfell gains life as a
planaineswalker so definitely some super
friends action happening in 10 new
bruise. Uh, and of course the Johnny
plays a walker, we'll see later, had
literally cares about life gain. Uh, so
that's kind of sweet. There's a lot
going on here, uh, with this card, uh,
than than at face value, which really
really cool. Other card I think would be
pretty cool and limited. This one
requires a little more oomph, but I
think even just like three mana empower
chase five is I guess that's not really
good enough, but it's it's still it's
close and it's pretty cool. Card's
really cool. Uh, big fan of of the
entire empower chase mechanic. Like huge
fan. Then we have Yoshimaru, beloved
companion. Three mana 42. If one or more
plus counters be put on a creature you
control, put that many plus one and you
send six mana to put a counter on a
creature you control. Legendary creature
you control, effectively two counters,
right? Uh, so the archetype for red
white in the set is this counter stuff
going on. This would be better in that.
So it scales pretty well. Not a really
exciting card at two for three, but it's
a fine limited filler card uh for the
archetypes that want it, but pretty
pretty eh. Then we have your fate ends
here.
>> Get off my plane.
>> Really good card to name with uh needle
or whatever if you're trying to close
the game out. But the meta for a instant
destroy creature with mana or planes
walker mana value three or greater and
surveil one. So pretty close to uh to
hero's downfall in white, you know,
can't kill small things. Can't kill
tokens either, which kind of matters. Um
but this card's pretty good, you know,
phenomenal limited card. Like banger
removal spell for limited constructed
might be like a one of or two of in some
decks. Just looking for like that extra
piece of removal. It's a little clunky,
but very versatile. Surveilling one is
nice, too. Uh card's very good. You
know, great limited card constructed
fringe, but still pretty cool.
The J token does not have mana value, so
it can't kill a J token. And then we
have Euro, Blade of the Mighty. This is
a uh the alternate universe of Eureo.
Four mana 4 A23. During combat, players
can't cast spells or activate abilities
that aren't mana abilities. That is both
sided. So you as well, so awkward with
your pump spells. Ever creature control
attacks alone. Uh it gains double strike
till end of turn, which is pretty good.
Um two, three body for four is pretty
sketch. Uh, but the ability is quite
powerful. It's also an ability where you
can't play your pump spells, they can't
play the removal spells. So, it's like,
you know, a little bit of double-edged
sword, but kind of cool. Um,
yeah, I don't know. Cards interesting
for limited. Not really much else
constructed. Uh, but
yeah, I don't know. It's fine.
Then we have Flickering Hound, our first
rare. And this card was very close to me
uh to getting the trap award. Gave it
somewhere else. Uh but flickering on is
a mirrored version. Again, there are
mirrored versions. This is not
technically a mirrored card. Uh as there
is no displacer kitten k k k k k k k k k
k k k k k k k k k k k kitten in the set,
but there are a lot of cards in a set
kind of planner chaos style taking a
card from Magic's history and giving it
kind of like a a twist. So flickering
hound is a twist on displacer kitten. Uh
whereas two for four, whenever you cast
a creature spell, you get to blink a
creature you control uh rather than
non-creature spell blinking things. Uh
think this card is pretty sketch
honestly. A lot of what makes this place
curtain good is how it works with zero
mana artifacts. Uh you know, bouncing
things with a ferryy or whatever else it
might be. Uh unless you're playing or
doctor and memight and friends, you
can't really uh do that here. So, I
think this two [music] two for four is
pretty sketch uh overall and a card that
probably shouldn't see any serious play
really at all. Fun commander card, fun
kind of, you know, aspirational card,
but yeah, and then in limited, I mean,
if you have a ton when it comes to play
effect, sure, but two for four is a
really tough cell of a stat line. Uh so,
yeah, not not a fan uh flickering out.
Cool. Artha
germinate recruits the meta for an
instant make x tut twos or x the amount
of life you gain this turn. So in modern
you can nourishing sh gain 15 life and
make 15 two twos on turn three which is
you know cool I guess.
>> Uh in the real world though I think this
card is pretty rough. Um this is the
kind of card where if it works it'll be
quite good. when it doesn't work, it's
just a blank. And like how many tokens
does this need to make for you to be
really happy with it? I would say at
least three. I don't think two is
enough. Uh so making three or four
tokens, cool, but like lot of setup, lot
of volatility. I I feel like if you're
playing a life gain deck, um you know,
you just want to be a little more
efficient and like, you know, lean in
this. There's already a lot of A plus B
going on in the life gain deck. I don't
think this card lines up well there. The
ceiling's pretty high, but the floor is
just stone nothing. Uh, also awkward
because it doesn't play well with soul
warden effects where you know when you
play a creature gain one life. Uh, this
is the creatures. So, you would gain a
bunch of life when you play this but you
need to have a whole bunch of things
going too. So, the ceiling is very very
high. Um, that is fair, but I don't
think his card's that great. I think in
limited it's like kind of fine if you're
playing a bunch of life gain effects.
you know, getting three two or two twos
could be fine, but yeah, I think this
card is very, very risky, and folks are
going to be tantalized by the high
ceiling only to fall into the basement
and be like, "Oh my god, what was I
thinking, you know?" So, uh, yeah.
>> No, you can't. Don't even try.
>> Not really a fan of this one. We have a
card I am a fan of, Gideon's Memorial.
And, uh, this is a card that, if you
remember the common that returns a
legendary permanent from your graveyard,
this is a cool one to return. uh to an
artifact. It gives all of your tokens
plus one pluso and vigilance which is
pretty good. It also taps to add a mana
of any color for a planaineswalker which
is pretty sweet. And on top of all of
that two mana and discard a card and you
get Gideon's approach uh four to attack
or blocker.
That's awesome. Uh this card is
fantastic. like the uh it almost has the
effect of uh intangible virtue which is
a card that was banned at one point uh
in I think block instructed uh but
that's great being a matter rocker plan
walkers is also great uh casting your
else with the turn early there are a
bunch bunch of good walkers in the set
and it's a mana fixer too and then the
problem is that if it didn't have the
buyout like how many of his card can you
play you know like what two maybe but
with the buyout you just play four great
whatever play four of his card and go
nuts Uh, so you will definitely
definitely definitely see this card in
10 New Bruce hype next Wednesday. Uh,
for sure in some sort of Super Friends
deck. Uh, but yeah, thanks card's
awesome. Really really cool card. Um,
it's not a spell either. So you can like
hit a voice of victory with it. You can
play it through counter spells. Awesome
stuff. Love this card. Think it's great.
Unlimited's also great because Gideon's
approach is just a fine card and maybe
you are playing Planaines Walkers and
tokens that could do that too. So
think's great. Uh, awesome awesome card.
Gideon's Memorial. No award. Uh, but
it's fantastic. Great art, too.
Guiding Hydra is next. There's some
humor here in the fact that this thing
with a bunch of eyes and arms that seems
to be going in every direction is
guiding you. Doesn't seem like it'd be
very good at that. Uh, if you're asking
me,
>> that's rough, buddy.
>> But, uh, yeah, white next for a one
zero. And there's X counters on it. And
beginning of combat in your turn, you
may remove a counter from this card. if
you do put a counter on each other
creature you control.
[music]
>> Another card that I kind of want to give
a trap award to, uh, but it's going
somewhere else. I think this card's
super sketch. Uh, so for three mana, you
get a 2-1 that can pump the team. Um,
which is not really great in modern day
limited. There's just better ways to do
stuff like that. Uh, and uh, yeah, we
had a bit of Cathian. Sorry. Yeah, lost
where I was. But yeah, was pretty
sketch. Um, as far as go wide stuff
goes, there are better ways to pump the
team. And if you're going wide, you're
you're in pretty good shape anyway. I'd
say you have one other creature in play
or other creatures in play. I think this
card is heinous. Uh, it is cute with
inkeeper talent or whatever and stuff.
Uh, like some like like doubling
effects, but I think overall this card's
pretty bad. Going to be a great card in
limited, like a big time, you know,
rare, like maybe even like a splashable
rare unlimited. You just cast it for six
and just go nuts. Uh, but I think
overall this card is pretty sketched as
inconstructed and uh, honestly
unplayable, but a lot less exciting than
it looks. Uh, and very, very scary art.
I don't like that. Cool, though. Don't
laugh at me. Kindred Judgment. Seven
metaphor sorcery. Choose a type and
destroy all creatures that aren't of a
chosen type. So, Doomscar, baby. Um, we
already have uh, winnowing, right? the
convoke spell from Lauren Eclipse, which
is pretty close to this. Uh, seven mans
a lot, you know. Um, think this card is
it's kind of cool. It feels more like a
commander card than anything else. Seven
is just so much in your Kindred deck.
So, I think this is mostly just like
commander card. It's very expensive for
limited, although it is really good as a
one-sided wrath if you're doing some
stuff. Uh, but yeah, biggest card is
meh. Um, commander card. Have fun,
commander players.
Liliana the faultless. What if Liliana
was a white card, not a black card?
Well, I'll tell you. What matter for one
one? Whenever another creature or planes
walker you control enters, you gain one
life. So, soul warden and then one tap
discard a card. Another creature you
control or planes walker gains hexroof
end of turn. So, uh a soul warden with a
lot of upside here is pretty sweet.
Again, soul warden is already almost
playable in standard. Uh that one two
rabbit or whatever in the life gain
decks does the thing. This does that
pretty well. Of course, being a
legendary is a little awkward, but any
elemental legend, you know, on Mox Amber
in old formats, too, as a thing. Uh, and
then the protection effect is, you know,
it's not amazing. You have to discard a
card also. So, pretty hefty cost for the
most part. There's just a fancy soul
warden with some cool art. Uh, but
that's fine, honestly. So, uh, for
construct life gain decks, cool for
limited, if you're if you're playing the
life game deck and limited, this card
seems great. Otherwise, little less
exciting. Uh, and of course, it's only
your stuff, not your, uh, opponent's
stuff either. a ton of true soul warden.
Uh so yeah, card's fine. Uh could have
honestly it could have been uncommon I
feel like almost but sure.
Loyal tutor.
>> All right. Now we come to our trap card.
Loyal tutor uh enters the cycle of the
Mirage tutors. These are the one mana
tutors uh that search for a card but
puts it on top of your library rather
than in your hand. Mystical Tutor,
Vampiric Tutor, Worldly Tutor, and so on
and so forth. Um, the problem is that
those cards are kind of bad. Um, they're
really good in the sense where if you're
putting together a combo, they're
insane, right? Mystical tutor for show
and tell, worldly tutor for my creature
combo piece, vamp tutor for oath the
druids, whatever. They're busted in that
context, but they're pretty tame
otherwise. For example, I think a
mystical tutor or vampiric tutor was
legal in standard. they would see
effectively zero play. Uh maybe in some
weird spots where certain things are
happening, whatever, but for the most
part, it is just card disadvantage. It
is just one mana, go down a card and try
and find the right piece, and that's not
really worth it. Uh so
you're not really comboing with tutors.
Um with planes walkers, I mean, uh this
is not going to put together some combo.
It's an old format. Uh, and uh, I think
this card is just kind of really really
ass like like I struggle to imagine a
deck that would ever want to play this
card. Like maybe in commander for some
weird like planes walker combo in
commander or something. Sure. Uh, but
seeing this card knowing the pedigree of
vampiric tutor, mystical tutor, I think
it'd be really easy to be like, "Wow,
this card's awesome. I just get a
planaineswalker and it's in standard.
Cool." You know, but overall I think
this card is is pretty meh. Uh, I think
this card's mostly unplayable. unless
you're in a really weird spot of doing
some weird combos of a commander or
whatever else it might be. But yeah, I
think as cards seeing play in standard,
it would be extremely unlikely and uh
don't play it limited either. Yeah, even
in modern like I don't even know what
the what the the the baseline to play
this card would be. So your trap card is
loyal tutor not so loyal here.
Lyra, Archangel of Dawn. Three mana for
a three- three flyer. If you gain life,
put a counter on each angel you control.
So, at its absolute base level, this is
a flying a Johnny's Pridemate. So, it'll
pump itself. Uh, so unlimited, this card
is a bonkers card. Uh, really, really
good constructive. There is some angel
stuff in standard right now. Uh, Giata
is in Foundations. Uh, I think Lyra 5 is
also in Foundations, too. So, there is a
bit of an angel Kindred thing going on
with some life gain stuff. Um, I don't
think that's good enough in standard
probably, but it's there if you want to
try and go for it. Maybe we will
continue 10 new bruise. I don't know.
There's so much fun stuff to play that
it might not happen, but uh but yeah, it
is there. I guess it's a great limited
card, but for the most part, probably
not there uh and constructed. Uh but
yeah, maybe in older formats, too.
There's a a uh angel deck in Pioneer.
Could be like a two of in that deck for
sure. But uh yeah,
then we come to the really kind of
creepy art. I don't like it. uh
repurpose enforcer [music]
which is our sleeper card of white to
metaphor a 32 human soldier
creature attacks empower chase x where x
is the number of creatures you control
noting this is not attacking it's just
things you have uh and that's really
quite good um say I have three creatures
in play which is not a difficult bar to
hit right I go one drop two drop turn
three play creature and attack this is
pack and draw card which is awesome. Uh
then of course there's the fact that
like if you are doing planes walker
stuff this you can keep kind of putting
that up. Maybe you're playing a token
deck and go go up that way too. This
could be a sideboard card for your your
like super friends deck making tokens or
whatever. A lot of the white walkers
make tokens anyway so you can not have a
lot of creatures in your deck but have a
lot of creatures in that way. Uh I think
this card's awesome. I think this card
is a big time sleeper. It's creepy as
hell which I don't like very much. Uh, I
think this card's awesome. Fine stat
line, good creature type, uh, card sick,
you know, and then also, you know, if
you're playing as a sweeper deck, right?
Say you play your third creature, attack
with this, put Jason play, and they
wrath you. Now you draw card, which is
great. Um, card is awesome. Really,
really good card. Insane unlimited.
Also, again, if you just have one big
attack, make a Jace five. Sick. That's
really, really good. So, love it. Big
fan. uh repurposed enforcer sleeper card
for white for reality fracture.
And then we come to our mythics. A
Johnny Resolute one half of the Johnny
mirrored pair. The other Johnny is red.
And more on that in a bit. But a Johnny
Resolute is one of uh this what the the
third or fourth mana planaineswalker.
Now we got what Tibble red and six. uh
the Jace you can't play in the first few
turns is really isn't really you know
count it's like a half a two mana
planaineswalker so that's a big deal
Johnny resolute is two mana for a two
loyalty planaineswalker whenever you
gain life put a loyalty counter on a
Johnny so it's like a Johnny's pridemate
uh planaineswalker
zero mana gain one life so bas basically
plus one gain one life uh and now you
can go minus four and literally make an
a Johnny's pride mate uh So that's kind
of sweet.
>> We have technology
>> minus 10. Get an emblem, pump your team,
whatever. This is mostly um mostly just
a engine to like keep either a gaining
life or b making pride mates, which is
cool because it plays both sides of the
ball. This card's nice. I'm a big fan of
this card. Um again, there's a life gain
deck already that's pretty good in
standard. Getting an insane amount of
tools in this set, so I would not be
surprised to see this card to see play
in standard. Uh card's great. And then
limited discard's awesome too. I think
even if you just play it, gain a life,
gain a life, gain a life, make a token
or whatever. Pretty cool. Um, yeah,
really, really cool stuff. Uh, it is up
against a mirrored pair, Johnny. It's
also really good. We'll see about in
red. Uh, but again, they might not be in
the same pack because you have, again,
reminder how packs work for mirrored
pairs. There will always be one mirrored
pair. So, the white a Johnny and the red
a Johnny and then a third
random mirrored pair card to obscure uh
that you know you didn't take one or the
other in limited. So, uh could be in a
pack by itself with you know the Liliana
mirrored pair or whatever else. So, not
a guarantee uh in limited.
Great card though. Really, really cool.
Enlightened Confident. Another card that
could have gotten the uh the trap award
unfortunately.
Dark confident on proper is literally
legal and standard and almost
unplayable. And now we have enlightened
confident which is two for a two-1
lifelink.
Kind of a really ass backwards way to uh
to dark confidant to kind of backwards.
End step. If you gain life this turn,
surveil one. If you put a card of mana
value less than or equal to the number
of life you gain this turn into your
graveyard this way, put it into your
hand. So I gain three life. Whatever.
endstep surveil one. If I if I bin it
and it costs three or less, it goes to
my hand. Uh if it's a land, it's a
freebie, just like Dark Confidant, which
is pretty cool. That being said,
um I don't know, you know, there's a lot
of life gain cards around. It's kind of
cute as a way to draw cards in a life
gain deck, but like I don't know if
there's room, honestly. Having lifelink
itself is nice. It'll trigger itself,
but of course, two one body is super
fragile. Um I don't know. Think this
card is kind of sketchy. if a lot of
work for not a huge payoff. I think
there are just better life gain cards
and just better cards in general. Screw
a limited card. It's two unlikely two
which is fine. Uh but yeah, think this
card is I don't know. It might be all
right in the life gain deck, but we'll
see. But I think it's going to play a
little worse than it looks. Um maybe
we'll build an eight confidant deck.
It's four dark confidant for this card.
Really, really stick it to them, you
know. But yeah, return to the light
realms. That's right. The light realms.
Uh not the dark realms. not Rise of the
Dark Realms. This is the white version
of that big card that returns all all
creatures from all graveyards. This
returns all non-land permanent cards
from your graveyard to the battlefield.
So, artifacts, enchantments, planes,
walkers, and more. I mean, it costs nine
mana. If you cast it limited, you'll win
the game if you cast it in lil, which is
pretty hard to do. Construct get far too
expensive. Fun commander card, but
nothing more.
So to recap, in white, prophesized end
is our best in show. Repurpose enforcer
is our sleeper card. Loyal tutor is our
trap card and campus crier is the
bombing common. Blue's coming up on
stream for YouTube folks. We have seven
videos broken into sections of blue
coming up after that a little bit. So
look for that. Of course, like, comment,
subscribe, support the content as
always. And don't forget, we got 10 new
brews happening uh on Wednesday on the
early access. It's going to be a lot of
fun. I cannot wait because that looks so
cool. And then the week following will
be the premier bronze mythic and our
first draft subet uh as well. So really
cool stuff. Uh blue is coming up at
YouTube folks. Peace.